<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>灵性的升进</title>
  
  <subtitle>获得自觉，提升灵性</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mataji.cn/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://mataji.cn/"/>
  <updated>2024-11-04T14:23:07.474Z</updated>
  <id>http://mataji.cn/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>moksha</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>sahaja</title>
    <link href="http://mataji.cn/2024/11/04/sahaja/"/>
    <id>http://mataji.cn/2024/11/04/sahaja/</id>
    <published>2024-11-04T14:21:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-11-04T14:23:07.474Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>-01-25 Talk To Sahaja Yogis: Must Listen Every Day</p><h4 id=""><a href="#" class="headerlink" title=""></a></h4><p>Sahaja has been created for you only. But for mankind to understand  Sahaja Yoga is not so easy. Because if some very great thing is obtained effortlessly, a lacking remains for its importance, its measure, faith  and devotion for that Shakti, to absorb it with complete attention  within through hard work. That’s why you see that mostly Sahaja Yogis  are very casual. But those other Swamis, as you know, how they put  people into meditation, and how they take advantage of them. Those who  take money from you, make you work hard and make you stand on your  heads, make you exercise, etc.</p><p>So your ego gets satisfied with it and you get stuck to it. You must  have seen such people who have given their all, their money, etc and  then sweep the floors for these Sadhus. The getting of Sahaja Yoga is  done so effortlessly [sahaja] that people remain casual towards it. Like we got our eye so effortlessly, so we are so casual about it. We have  no value that this eye is so precious. But the day we get a slight pain  in the eye then we realize, “O God!” That is why it is so necessary to  get <em>badhas</em>. If there are no <em>badhas</em> then Sahaja Yogis will never bother.</p><p>(A person in the audience asks about <em>badhas</em>. Shri Mataji answers.) <em>Badha</em> is dependent on you. Till you catch, there is <em>badha</em>. What to do? There are some people who have got Realisation and they have gone beyond. <em>Badha</em> doesn’t catch them. They never get caught up. Because there are a lot of merits [Punyas] from their past lives. But they should also be alert. They  should not forget that, “We do not catch so we are something special”,  doesn’t matter.</p><p>To be casual towards Sahaja Yoga will cost us dearly! If you are  casual towards your eye then it does not matter because there is someone ready to look after your eyes, hands, feet, body. You don’t have to  look after that. But you have to look after your Sahaja Yoga. There is a lot of difference between the two. Someone will look after your body,  and all that is three dimensional will be looked after, but you yourself have to see to Sahaja Yoga. We have to grow in it, but we are so casual that even if a person is sitting in our neighbourhood we will not talk  about it. Whoever you meet, talk about it. You will have to give this  dedication about Sahaja Yoga. There are many people who… Their bodies  are separate.</p><p>Like yesterday, one girl had a <em>badha,</em> and when her brother came he got his Realisation . In this world there are  many parts of you all over, whom you have to gather. This is also a very big Sahaja Yoga. Even in your own house how can someone live without  Sahaja Yoga, “If you live in my house then you all will have to come to  Sahaja Yoga. You will have to get Realisation and keep no <em>badha</em>.” There should be an insistence but there is no need to get angry. You  must tell them. This casualness will not do. Sahaja Yoga will have to be established with eating, waking, with every breath being taken. Because if you think of yourself as something special, if you think that your  body is a temple and there is something special about it then the voice  of the Temple bells must keep ringing. Otherwise it will go to waste.  Sahaja Yoga can also go to waste. Please understand this!</p><p>Also the second thing I better tell you that without Sahaja Yoga you  now have no personality. Without it you have no blossoming. Without that you have no place. Because when you have come to the Kingdom of God you will have to take its citizenship.</p><p>Yesterday one family member came and he said that, Yesterday I went  to Gajanan Maharaj.” “Who is this Gajanan Maharaj?” I saw that Agnya  Chakra, Vishuddhi chakra, three chakras were catching. He said that he  catches with the photo of Gajanan Maharaj. I said, “Here I am your  sister sitting in your own house and why did you go to Gajanan Maharaj?” First he said, “No, he is a saint.” I said, “At least check the  vibrations that he is a saint or not?” They just went casually. They  should also see, “Is this Sahaja Yoga?” After becoming a king then  wanting to become a beggar, such people should be thrown out! But they  said they did not become beggars deliberately. It was in casualness that they went off there, “What to do, our wife is like this, what could we  do?” “What could we do our father is like that.” “Our daughter said,  ‘Let’s go’ so we went..” So then they came and said, “Mataji, my Agnya  Chakra got caught. My stomach chakra got caught.” Three chakras of  theirs got caught yesterday. “I am your real sister sitting here then  what was the need for you to go to Gajanan Maharaj?” Then they said,  ”Our state has gone really bad so now we will go to Sai Baba.” So I told them that, “You better come here and then go to Sai Baba otherwise the  same will happen there. What wisdom will you gain there? Thousands go  there, so what is it you want there? You want material things from Sai  Baba? Will these desires of human beings get fulfilled? You have got all materially. Now what is it you are wanting? You have got kingdoms,  palaces now what do you want?”</p><p>The one who has come to give, and what you have to get, is of great  importance for humanity. God has made you with great care. All this  filth which you have collected in your brain, just throw it all away!  You have collected all these useless things, all this junk in this  temple of yourself. Establish this temple. In every heart you have to  light lamps. Purify your house, purify your family, and purify your  society. You are very concerned about your relatives. Your mother in law has come, “I have to do for her; I have to give her.” What will your  mother-in-law give you? She will beat you with shoes! You must know that your relatives are the Sahaja Yogis. There are no other relatives  besides Sahaja Yogis. Sahaja Yogis are the relatives of Sahaja Yogis,  because they speak another language, their ways are different; their  manner is different. For this you will have to burn your life force  [Prana]. For this you will have to share Love. Love will flow on the  edge of your Attention [Chitta]. First make your Attention alright. Make it light. If you keep everything else on your attention how will Sahaja Yoga come? It is coming down through your Attention, [Chitta] only. God is waiting to pour this into you, but where is your attention? In two  minutes your attention runs here and there. Just put your attention at  God’s feet. He does not want your money, wealth or anything else. Keep  this all with you. This is the stupidity of humans. And which you have  gathered, what is the importance of all this? Give importance to your  attention because it is on this attention that God will come. He has  made you young like 20-year olds. Your bodies have healed; He has made  your hearts Pure. Collective Consciousness has come into you. Now what?  You are still running after this or the other. You consider all those  things more important. In your past lives you had earned all this  rubbish and left it all behind. Now again you will collect all this  wealth and you will again leave it all behind. To live casually for a  Sahaja Yogi is a very dangerous thing. What we call as carelessness.  There is a great war going on. You know how other ways and methods have  got started for destruction.</p><p>Sahaja Yoga is like a lotus standing in these murky waters. Delicate, Fragrant, Beautiful, and you are the petals of that lotus. Any filth  which falls on you will just slide off when you get to know that you are lotuses. So if any chakra is catching then get rid of the filth. You  are lotuses; you have been made into lotuses so if any filth falls onto  the lotus then the lotus should just throw it off. Each one of you will  have to be awakened towards Sahaja Yoga if you have to take the boat of  Sahaja Yoga across. Don’t sit with your tiny and petty problems of your  relatives, homes, and your small petty questions. Till when are you  going to keep hanging onto this filth? None of this lot is going to side with you, “Will my son or daughter get married?” Etc. If it happens  fine and if it doesn’t then fine also. You will spend money there, try  and get a name there. And for Sahaja Yoga? You have no time for Sahaja  Yoga. The big thing is that people in India do not have too much money.  Their own monetary condition is not too good. But we must know that in  this India there are VIBRATIONS which control everything. Any other  country would have collapsed by now. You are living because of the  support of vibrations. What a great country this is! What a country you  are born in! You know this. I don’t know how to tell the foreigners  about the importance of the Devi. They don’t know what is the Devi, what is the Mother. They are such dirty people who don’t understand the  relationship of the Mother, I feel like crying. And you people have  become so casual. Like you shave your beard, you meditate in the same  way. How is this going to happen?</p><p>My brothers tell me, “Why are you killing yourself from morning to  evening? Something might go wrong with your health, and then what will  your husband tell us? You sleep at 4-5 am, day long you are working so  hard, why are you doing this, what are you going to get by this?” I can  fight alone but what benefits are you all going to get by it? To be  casual, to live casually, it is a dismal attitude towards yourself. It  is your own insult. It is like a king who has got all the wealth and he  is living casually. There are rules to ascend the throne! Are you going  to finish off Sahaja Yoga by taking up petty little things?! Clean your  insides; clean your heart. Leave this cunningness and clean your heart  and see if we are sitting in innocence. You are doing me no favour. What you were seeking from lifetimes you are getting that only. Now that you have, come to the last stage. Then what is this crazy behaviour? You  may not have seen the one who has come to the last stage, but I have  seen many like that. First I have to get them stuck to it. Stick! Stick! Stick!</p><p>Sometimes you have such thoughts that, ”What can we do? Our country  is so bad, and we are so poor here. And what good can we do to our  country?” Good that you don’t have money. I have given realization to so many people who are rich. Where are they? Just two or three! And they  too are such misers. There is no one here with too much money. I have  given Realisation to people with lakhs and crores. What are they doing?  Good there is not so much money and its nuisance! Good that this money  is not stuck to you. You have less money which is really good. I have  seen these rich, so called, these ministers, they have no joy like you  people have. They got their Realisation and then just sat down very  nicely! There they will sit with money! Big ministers, secretaries have  got Realisation! What have they done? God protect us from their egos!  Who is a secretary or a king with God? Answer this. Is Shri Mataji  right?</p><p>It is such an important day. Who am I before you? Go where you go for your Pujas to these temples! Are they going to come on this earth get  your own temple ready? These little children who just came in are more  lucky and blessed than you people. They are beyond money, positions and  all this foolishness. They just want Mataji. Yesterday some of these  children had come and they pleaded with their mothers to let them be at  my program for a longer time. I was not giving them any chocolate or  anything like that but they wanted to sit more with Mataji. They  understand more than you people. Leave your past and become like  children. You have become like children. What a beautiful form! You too  were like this my children. You all were like this. Where have you got  lost and become disfigured? Be afraid of your ugliness. Look at the  beauty of others. When I will go away, when the Mother leaves then it is the duty of the children to look after the house. When I come back, I  see that my children have been spreading Sahaja Yoga. But here when I  come, I see that 8-10 people have their Agnyas caught up, some others  have their Nabhi caught up and yet others have Vishuddhi caught up.  Someone went to someone else [guru], while others have fallen sick,  someone is in bad shape, someone’s wife is in hospital and another has  gone to the lunatic asylum. Oh, what happened? And don’t think you are  small people. You are very great people. All these “big” people are of  no use. They don’t get their Realisation! Know your greatness and then  talk. Open yourself and talk. One who speaks even one word in Sahaja  Yoga, then Sakshat Saraswati herself will come and sit there. I am  telling you. Just speak and then see. Just start talking about Sahaja  Yoga and you will see Saraswati coming into your voice. Start writing  about it and She will come into your writings. Take up any work in  Sahaja and Sakshat Hanuman is standing and he tells me, “Mother, with  whom should I stand?” Hanumanji is doing all your work. Take up any work in the name of your Mother, even of work of the world. For Sahaja Yoga  the five Immortals [<em>Chiranjeevs</em>] are standing there for you.  All these deities are ready with their Shaktis standing in the  background for you. And what do they see? That the actor who has come is in very bad shape. He is looking here and there. How will the drama go  on? This half-baked attitude won’t do.</p><p>“Mataji, I don’t get time to sit for meditation.” What do you mean  that you get no time? What is time meant for? Who has given you this  time? If you have no time for yourself then how will you get time for  God? How do you get no time? You should wake up at 4am. You have seen  your Mother. How many hours does She sleep? Wake up at 4 in the morning. Tell yourself. You have to go into meditation from 4 to 5 am. Throw  away your sleep! Give up keeping awake in the night. Stop talking with  useless people. Stop these useless associations, these relatives, all  these useless people. All these are <em>bhoots</em>. Have  we come here to waste our time on these people? I don’t spend even one  moment on telling you about Sahaja Yoga. Not even one moment. I have to  meet thousands of people from my husband’s office with whom I have to  shake hands at receptions; I use it for giving Realisation. They shake  hands and I give them Realisation. I see that he has got Realisation and I feel like laughing. Whichever country I go to I keep giving  Realisation. Whoever I speak to I keep giving Realisation. He keeps  talking and I keep on giving Realisation. He goes on talking about his  own things. Where I get a chance I keep giving Realisation. On Victoria  station a Pakistani Muslim was collecting tickets. The line was very  long and I was giving Realisation to him standing in the line and also  to the people standing in the line in front of me. Just as he gave me  the ticket and looked at Me, he got his Realisation. He gave all their  tickets and came and sat in my compartment, where I’m sitting alone. He  asked, ”Who are you? How do you have such an attraction?” I asked who he was. He said he is Hussain. So I told him to sit down and put his hands towards Me. He says, ”What is this happening? Cool? Who are You?” I  said, “See and recognize.”</p><p>I went to Rome, where many artists were sitting and painting  something. I gave one Realisation, then he got up and said something to  the one next to him, and then came and caught hold of my feet and  started crying bitterly, saying, ”Mother, When did You come?” I had gone there as the wife of a big officer with three or four official people  standing beside me. They all got embarrassed wondering what he is doing. He started saying, ”Mother, I have found You. In the night You had come in my dreams and said that, ‘I will wear such and such sari’ and You  have come in the same sari.”</p><p>Even a moment I think of nothing but Sahaja Yoga. I have forgotten  all the past. I have had big births, big people. I have forgotten all  the past and future. In this moment I remember only Sahaja Yoga and  nothing else. In the same way you people should think of Sahaja Yoga  only at each moment. Wherever you sit there should be Sahaja Yoga. Throw away your watches! Throw away this servitude to watches! Sahaja Yoga is your watch. If it is 12:30 it does not matter. It is 3 am. You are  sitting in Sahaja Yoga. Is Sahaja Yoga the servant of a watch or time?  We are not servants of any laws or rituals. We are standing only in  Sahaja Yoga. We keep sitting even if it takes time. Are we some servants of our stomachs? We are servants of no one. Everything keeps happening. It has to happen. Throw away this servitude to all your old bindings!  Throw away your watches! There is no system made for anything. In Sahaja Yoga there can never be a system. It makes its own system. Let it be  made. If you try and make systems then it will be destroyed. Don’t make  disciplines. Let the discipline of Sahaja Yoga keep moving within you.  Yes for those who have not got their realization for them the discipline is important. You do that. But those who have got realization such  people have to get their own discipline inside. The discipline will come by itself within. Sahaja Yogis have an inbuilt discipline. There is no  forgiveness for this. The one who is not a Sahaja Yogi should be  forgiven because he does not understand what discipline is. He only  knows the worldly discipline of the stick. Let the discipline come from  within and awaken from within for Sahaja Yogis. See how much you are  moving in the discipline of Sahaja. You are moving with its hand and  feet and rising with its waves. How much is the discipline tied with the waves of an ocean? You can tell sitting here at what time low tide or  high tide will come in London; who has tied its discipline; that you  have started tying other’s discipline! Learn to step into the discipline of the within. Learn to move in the directions and methods of within.  Its methods are moving. Don’t make your own. Make your own this, that.  Let’s get more into Sahaja, spend time for Sahaja. If you have to wear  watches then wear it for Sahaja Yoga. If you have to put alarm then let  it be for Sahaja Yoga.<br> (To a person who just entered: Come and sit.) You are all within my heart. Are you far away? You must understand this.</p><p>Even one leaf in this world cannot move without His discipline. Blend yourself in His discipline and merge in with His harmony. Harmonize  yourself totally. When it rises you rise, when it falls you fall. When  we try to do our own thing then we are left behind. Keep molding  yourself with it. This can happen only through Sahaja Yoga and not  through any worldly things.</p><p>There is only one way, which I have said a thousand times and I am  saying again, that your fortress is Thoughtlessness [Nirvicharita]! Know in Thoughtless Awareness and you will know everything. Anything you  have to do, go into Thoughtlessness. Once you do all worldly works in  thoughtless awareness then you will know that how dynamic it has become. Who has seen flowers bloom or become fruits? Who has seen the living  work of this world? It is being done. You are moving in the dynamism and in this living thing. It is coming from thoughtlessness. When you sit  there the whole world becomes pale. Try to make a habit of remaining in  Thoughtlessness. Every work is done through thoughtlessness and so will  yours. Your movement within has to be done by you. There is no age limit for this, that we have become old. You are not old. You have been  reborn hardly 3-4 years ago. You are just small little children. It is  not a question of age. One should remain in Thoughtlessness. This is  your place, your wealth, your strength [Shakti]. This is your form. This is your beauty. This is your life. Thoughtless! As soon as you are  thoughtless the outside methods, the whole of it starts moving in your  hands. Live in thoughtlessness. Over there, there is no Time, no  Direction, nor can anyone touch it. There is only a vision of the  Living. There is only a vision of Life and how it blooms. There is  vision of its Beauty, its Capability, its Prosperity and its Truth.  Watch it from where the stream of life is flowing.</p><p>But when you become brainless, or extremely stupid, then how will It  show you? Or to be heartless, without love, selfish, self centered, to  be ugly, to do atrocities, to keep on thinking about yourself, to think  that you are something very great, then how will It show you the way? In the movement of Sahaja Yoga there should be such beauty. While doing it there should be tremendous faith. When raising the Kundalini there  should be so much Devotion that it is like you are praying to the  Kundalini or Mother of another. There should be great respect for that  state, so much thought about it. In everything, in your behaviour, your  talk, the way you talk, in your touch, your laughter, and your tears, in everything there should be such a vision of your heart. It is massive.  This massiveness should show from within you. There should be a Vision  of the Skies within you. The Purity of Water should reflect from within  you. The Brilliance of the Sun should show from your face, the Coolness  of the Moon should flow from within you. Flowing everywhere, you should  be like the Wind. Your Breath is beating in everyone at this time. Know  this! Don’t play with your life. By being extremely reverent and humble  just accept it, the new life the Divine is putting within us. May you  accept His Grace, His Love. You don’t need to bathe or wash your hands  for it, you need to do nothing but clean your heart. Clean your heart,  “O God, please clean our hearts and make us leave our cunning and  deceitful ways.” Clean your hearts as He is going to descend in the  lotus of your hearts. Clean your hearts. Are our hearts clean? Who are  you deceiving? To whom are you telling lies? You are all one. I can  never say to one person only. I am speaking to each one of you that you  are all in one body; and that too in my body. You are my projection. I  am telling myself. To whom else shall I say? Who is the other?</p><p>When you are sick, I feel pain within just like I myself have got  sick. And when you are happy then I feel tremendous joy just like I have myself become happy. When you are unhappy then I too don’t enjoy any  joy. I keep awake night and day for you.</p><p>Whatever or whichever way you can do, one must give time, give full  time. Now we are going to make an ashram, so the ones who have money can give money. You will have to give. You spend money here and there. Of  what use has it been your spending money here and there. I don’t need  your money. I need nothing. I don’t need to spend anywhere. This ashram  is being made for you, your brothers and sisters, who are going to live  there. Now these realized children are being born, they need a school  and someone who can look after them. Give money for that. How will the  money come? Any money that comes from you is very important. Such people come here who do not want to spend even one rupee. There are not such  poor people here – if that is the case then it is alright. But those who cannot give even one rupee can such people be Sahaja Yogis? I get  really amazed that they trouble for giving one rupee or five rupees! You will have to give in thousands. Who has given you this money? I don’t  want it. What can you give me? At least give for yourself, for your  children, for your benefit. Tomorrow you yourself will come and live in  those ashrams. I know it. There is no need to be such misers or be  freeloaders. Live like kings. Just like I don’t eat for free you should  also not eat for free.</p><p>Whoever can do, do. One who has time, give time. One who can work,  then work. One who has to give realization, then give realization. One  has to take out the <em>bhoots</em> then take out the <em>bhoots</em>. Do for Sahaja Yoga. You will have to. Without doing so your ego will  not die, and neither will your super ego die unless and until you do not do something for Sahaja Yoga. Again your Agnya will catch, “Mataji, my  head is caught.” “Mataji my daughter ran away.” “Mataji, such and such  happened to my father.” It will happen. I don’t do anything. The Ganas  don’t do anything. Wherever you have a weakness, there only the <em>bhoots</em> will catch you. They don’t catch Me. Why don’t they catch Me?</p><p>“What has Mataji given us! She has given so much to someone else.”  Ach! He had to get so he got it. What you have got is no less. You have  no value for what you have got. There should be a satisfaction within.  Catch hold of that Satisfaction. Stand in that satisfaction. How can I  tell you? There are also computers and points about this. Press the  Satisfaction key and Satisfaction gets awakened within. Press another  key and your Innocence will awaken. Press another and Truth will awaken. This is all within you. By pressing the fingers, the whole program can  get set. But first at least there should be innocence. There should be  some satisfaction otherwise when you press the finger what will come  out? Vacuum? One who has pressed Satisfaction has arrived at  Satisfaction. They have arrived at wealth. They are sitting in wealth.  Some have collected your wealth from years by burning your bodies for  years and are now standing before you. In the same way you must collect  things one by one: Satisfaction, come into Innocence, come into Wealth,  come into Beauty, come into Truth, come into Love. All the buttons are  there.</p><p>How are we going to do it, how will we do it? There is no word like,  “How will we…?” in Sahaja Yoga. Whatever you want to earn, you can  within yourself. You can earn satisfaction within yourself; you can earn everything within yourself. Press the button and whatever you want will keep on coming to you. You will become a machine within. I can’t  understand how to get that attainment within you and join you.</p><p>Let us now go into Meditation.</p><h4 id="English-Translation-from-Hindi-Version-2"><a href="#English-Translation-from-Hindi-Version-2" class="headerlink" title="[English Translation from Hindi Version 2]"></a>[English Translation from Hindi Version 2]</h4><p>Sahaja Yoga has emerged, but it is not so easy for a human to  understand Sahaja Yoga. If you get a great thing like Sahaja Yoga so  easily, its greatness, its assessment, reverence for the shakti,  devotion for the Shakti, the hard work required to fully integrate it  inside with full mind, all these things will be lacking. That is why you notice that many are very casual. But the other swamijis, you know how  they consider the people, and how they exploit them. They take money  from you, make you do hard work, make you stand on your head, make you  do bodily work, some or other hard work so that your ego gets satisfied a little bit and you stick to it. You may also have seen such people, who give away everything they have, like money, etc. to these swamijis and  then they sweep at Swamiji’s place. One gets Sahaja Yoga with such ease, they are casual towards it. Like they got their eyes so easily, they  are casual, they do not know the value of these eyes. But the day we  have a problem with the eye, we will say ‘Oh, God’. That is why one must have difficulties. If there is no difficulty, the Sahaja Yogi will not  care for it at all. … Audience talk..unclear.. How long difficulties  will be there will depend on you, it will be there till you hold on to  them, what can be done about it?</p><p>There are some people, you know, once they are realised, they are  realised; it will not touch them. They will never have difficulties; it  is due to the Punyas (good deeds) from their previous lives. They should also be alert. They should not be unduly happy, ‘We do not have any  difficulty, so we are special, no problem’. Being casual towards Sahaja  Yoga will prove costly. If you are casual towards yourself, there is no  harm, because there is someone to look after your eyes, hands, legs,  body-there is someone to look after, ready. You don’t have to look after it. But your Sahaja Yoga, you have to look after yourselves. There is a big difference between the two. All your body will be managed, whatever other things which, I call your three dimensions, will all be managed.  But your Sahaja Yoga, only you have to practice. You have to flow in  that, but you are so casual, so casual, even if someone is sitting next  to you, you don’t tell him, meet him, talk about this and dedicate to  Sahaja Yoga. There are many people and different parts of the body –  (alluding to the Sahaja Yogis)- are separated.</p><p>Yesterday a girl had a problem and her brother came, he got  realisation in a split second. Lots of your limbs have fallen in this  world and you have to gather them, even that is a big Sahaja Yoga. In  your own house, how can one be outside Sahaja Yoga? If you are in my  house, you have to come to Sahaja Yoga, get realisation and you should  not have any problem. You should insist, you should not get angry with  them. You have to tell them about this, talk about this, but you should  not be casual. Eat, rise, sit and as you take a breath and with every  breath, you have to propose Sahaja Yoga. Because, if you consider  yourself a special form, and if you think that there is something  special about your temple, there should be ringing of bells all the  time, otherwise it will be a waste. Sahaja Yoga also can go waste. You  understand this. Another thing I want to tell you is that without Sahaja Yoga, you do not have a personality now. Without that there is no glow. Without that there is no acceptance. If you come into the kingdom of  God, you have to take citizenship!</p><p>I heard from many people, my brother came yesterday, he said’ ‘I went to Gajanand Maharaj’. I do not know who Gajanand Maharaj is. Phadke  talked about Gajanand Maharaj. Then, I saw that Agnya chakra, Vishuddhi  chakra, and another chakra – three chakras were caught up. He told his  experience that he gets a catch from his photograph itself. Three  chakras were caught up. I said, ‘I am your sister sitting here and why  did you go to Gajanand Maharaj?’ He said ‘All told me, he is a saint’. I said check from Vibrations, whether he is a saint or not. He went  casually. He should have checked. Is this Sahaja Yoga? After becoming a  King, one who becomes a beggar, he should be removed. But you are  becoming a beggar knowingly. Went casually, went there also. What to do, my wife is like this, what to do, my father is like this what to do, my daughter said let us go and I went. Then what happened, After coming  back, Mataji, my Agnya chakra is caught up, have a catch in the stomach, Nabhi chakra is caught up, three chakras are caught up. I am your own  sister sitting here, who asked you to go to Gajanand Maharaj? Then we  thought our condition was bad, so let us go to Saibaba. Then I said,  first you come here, get the stomach fixed, then go to Saibaba. If you  go there also what wisdom will you get? Thousands go there, what happens there? What do you want to ask? Want to ask for material things from  Saibaba? When will man’s material desires be fulfilled? Everything is  done, what do you want materially? You have become a king, what do you  still want? What I have come to give, what you have to get, that is very important.</p><p>For the human race, God has made a human after a lot of  contemplation. There is so much dirt in your brains collected from here  and there, throw it away. You have collected a lot of useless things,  junk. Throw away from this temple and make that temple prestigious. Have to light a lamp in each and every heart. Purify your house, purify your family, purify your society. You care a lot for your relatives! You  have a lot of relatives. ‘I have come for them, my mother-in-law has  come, I have to give her, I have to do something for her. What will your mother-in-law give you, When you go, she will give you thrashing with  footwear. These are your relatives, Know that. You do not have any  relatives, other than these. Only a Sahaja Yogi is the relative of a  Sahaja Yogi because they speak a distinct language. Their ways are  different, their stride is different. You have to give your life. You  have to share your love. Love will flow on the edge of the mind, Correct your mind, make your mind light. If you keep so much in your mind, how  will Sahaja Yoga get in there? It is working on the mind, watch.</p><p>God is sitting to pour on you. But where is your attention? It keeps  wavering every two minutes. You have to put your attention at His feet,  He does not want your money, etc. Keep it with you. What is the  importance of all the collections made from deaths? Make your attention  important. God will descend on that mind. He has made you younger by ten to twenty years. Your body has become alright. Thoughts of your mind  have been purified. You have got collective consciousness. Now what?</p><p>Still, you are running after this and that. Do you attach more  importance to that? In your previous lives, you have earned a lot of  dung. You have left it here and gone. Again gather it! You will again  leave it here and go. It is very dangerous to be casual for a Sahaja  Yogi. This is called negligence. A big war has arisen. You know that  other ways of destruction have been kept ready. Sahaja Yoga is standing  like a lotus in this mud; delicate, aromatic, fragrant, beautiful and  you are petals of that. All the mud which is there will fall off once  you know that you are the lotus, you are not the mud. But by chance if a chakra catches, it is mud, remove it. You have been made a lotus. You  are the lotus and if the mud falls on the lotus, the lotus should throw  it away and also it is also not going to stick.</p><p>Everyone has to be aware of Sahaja Yoga. If you have to cross with  the ferry of Sahaja Yoga, don’t get bogged down by small problems of  family and small problems in the house. How long are you going to hold  onto this mud with your hand? There is no one to support you. The boy is to be married, the girl is to be married, it may happen, may not  happen. You will spend money on that. You will earn a name in that. And  for Sahaja Yoga, you have no time. The most important thing is that  Indians don’t have much money. if you look at it, their financial  condition is not that good. But we should know that vibrations are there only in India, which controls everything. If it were any other country  it would have collapsed by now. You are living only with the help of  those Vibrations. What a big country! You are born in such a great  country. You know everything. I don’t know how to tell the English about Devi mahatmyam, they have not read it. They don’t know what Devi is and what Maa is. They are such dirty people they don’t know what Maa is;  how can I tell them what Maa is, I feel like crying. And you have become so casual and you sit in meditation as if for a shave. How will it  happen?! My brothers asked me ‘why are you struggling day in and day  out? If your health gets affected, what will we tell your husband? You  sleep at night at 4 or 5 and the whole day you are working. Why are you  doing it? what are you going to get, we don’t understand’. Now they will not understand nor will I! When we both have an understanding then only something will happen.</p><p>I can fight it out alone, but how will you benefit from that? Being  casual, walking casually are signs of showing apathy towards yourself.  It’s disrespectful to yourself. The king who got the entire wealth is  being so casual. Rule, Relax! Are you going to finish Sahaja Yoga on  small issues? You clean your inner being, you clean your heart. Leave  the over smartness. Cleanse your heart and check ‘Are we sitting in  innocence?’ You are not doing a favour to me. It is for you; you are  getting what you have been asking, what you have been searching for  ages, you are getting. When you have reached the pinnacle, why are you  being mad? You may not have seen those who turn their face away when  they reach the pinnacle, but I have seen. First, you have to make them  stick. Have to keep on saying, ‘stick-on, stick on!’ Sometimes I think  of you like this; ‘what can we do? Things are so bad in our country. We  are poor people, we have our problems, how can we uplift the country,  Mataji? You have put us on a higher pedestal’.</p><p>It is good that you don’t have money. I have given realisation to so  many rich people here. Where are they? See only 2 or 4 here. They are  even very miserly, we don’t have a rich man among us. I have given  realisation to millionaires. What are they doing? It is good you don’t  have money, it is a hassle. Very little is sticking to you. Less money  is very good. I have seen rich people, people holding positions,  Ministers. They don’t have the happiness which you have. They get  realisation and sit back in style, and sit with a lot of money.  Ministers and Secretaries have got their realisation. What have they  done? God save us from their arrogance. For God who is Secretary and who is king? …….Marathi conversation of Shri Mataji….. They are better than you because they do not have the dirt of money. They do not have any  position, to make them stupid. They just want Mataji. Yesterday a few  children came. Their mother said, ‘let us go’. They were saying ‘let us  stay back’. They were not getting any chocolates, nothing. ‘We don’t  want any cinema, we only want Mataji. Let’s go to Mataji’. They know  more than you. You also become like them. Leave everything of the past  and become like them. Now you become children. How beautiful you are.  You are also like this, son! You were also like this. Now you have all  become deformed, disgusting. Be worried about it. See the beauty of  others.</p><p>I will go. When the mother is away it becomes the responsibility of  children to look after the house. When I come back I should see that My  children have spread Sahaja Yoga. Otherwise, I will see that someone has a catch of Agnya chakra, someone has a problem with the Nabhi chakra,  someone has Vishuddhi problem. Someone went there, someone went there.  Someone has fallen sick, someone is unwell, someone’s wife is in  hospital and someone is in a Lunatic Asylum. What has happened? Don’t  think that we are small people. You are a very great person. So-called  great people are useless, they don’t get their realisation. You realise  your greatness and talk. You talk openly. If one speaks one letter of  Sahaja Yoga, Goddess Saraswati will come and sit there, I am telling  you. You speak and see. You will experience it. Start talking about  Sahaja Yoga, Saraswati will be in your voice, you start writing,  Saraswati will be in your writing. Start any work Hanumana will stand  there with folded hands, Mother tell me, ‘with whom shall I stand?’  Hanuman Ji is doing all your work. Whatever work you take up in the name of Mataji whatever work you take in this world, whatever it may be, he  will do it.</p><p>For Sahaja Yoga work all the five Chiranjeevis- long lived-are  standing by. All of them are putting powers behind you and standing in  the background. And Nat Ji who has come, he is in a bad shape, he is  looking here and there. How will the play be composed? We don’t want a  half-hearted approach. ‘I don’t get time to meditate’. What do you mean I don’t get the time? For what do you have time? Who has given you time?  If you don’t get time for yourselves, God saves you. How do you not get  the time? Get up at 4 in the morning. You have woken up your Mother. How many hours does She sleep? Get up at 4 in the morning. Tell your mind, I have to meditate from 4 to 5. Throw away the sleep. Stop staying awake  in the nights, stop talking to useless people. Leave worthless  associations, leave aside relatives, they are all useless people. They  are all bhoots. Have we come to waste our time for them?</p><p>I don’t spend even one moment, you will be surprised, on anything  other than Sahaja Yoga. Thousands of people come to my husband’s office, whenever there is a reception; they all ask for their realisation Shake hands and they ask for realisation! Whichever country I go to, I give  realisation. They keep talking to me, I give realisation while talking. I see that they have got realisation in a split second. He keeps on  talking about so many things. Wherever I get an opportunity, I keep  giving realisation.</p><p>At Victoria station, there was a ticket collector. He was a Muslim.  When I was buying the ticket, there was a long queue and I was giving  realisation. Maybe he was from Pakistan-from wherever he maybe. I think  he was from Pakistan. While standing I was giving realisation and even  to others who were standing there, I was giving realisation. While he  was issuing a ticket to me, he looked at me and he got his realisation.  So he gave a ticket to all and came inside and sat inside my  compartment. I was sitting alone in that compartment. He asked Me, ‘Who  are You? Why is there so much attraction in you? I asked him, ‘who are  you?’. He said his name was Hussain. I said, ‘Sit down, Hussain mian’. I said, ‘Put your hand like this’. He said, ‘What is this cool breeze  coming? Who are you? I said, ‘See and recognise.’</p><p>I went to Rome. It is an incident that happened long back. Many  artists were sitting there. They were painting something. Gave  realisation to one. He got up, told something to someone and fell at my  feet, sat, caught hold of both My feet and started crying, saying  loudly, ‘Mother, when did you come?’ I went there as the wife of an  officer; three people were standing on this side and four people on that side. Those people were embarrassed- what is this man doing? He said,  ‘No Mother, I found You. I saw You in my dream last night. You said you  will come wearing a white sari. And you have come wearing that’.</p><p>Even for one moment, I can’t think of anything other than Sahaja  Yoga. I have forgotten all my past, there have been great lives, they  have all become great. I have forgotten everything, all the details. I  only remember Sahaja Yoga. I don’t remember anything. In the same way.  every moment you have to think of Sahaja Yoga, wherever you are sitting  there itself. Throw away your watches first. Throw away slavery to  watches. Become a slave of Sahaja Yoga, Sahaja Yoga is your watch. It  was 12:30, no harm, you were sitting there, it is 3 you were still  sitting there. You were sitting in Sahaja Yoga. Is Sahaja Yoga slave of  the watch or time? We are not slaves of any regulation or law. We are  only standing in Sahaja Yoga. Whatever time it may take, we will sit  there. Wherever we are sitting, we will sit there. Are we slaves to the  stomach that we have to eat on time? We are not slaves to anything.  Everything keeps happening, it is going to happen.</p><p>First of all, you leave your slavery of everything, whatever old  slavery is there leave it. First of all, throw away watches. No system  has been made for anything. No system can be made in Sahaja Yoga. Its  own systems are being made, let them be made. If you make the system,  that will be hailed. Don’t enforce discipline. Let its discipline be  working inside. Yes, those who have not got their realisation,  discipline is required; you enforce it. But those who are realised, they have to enforce discipline inside them. The discipline will happen  inside by itself. Sahaja Yogi has an inner discipline. But if there is  indiscipline here, it can’t be forgiven. But one who is not a Sahaja  Yogi, forgive him because he does not know what discipline is. He knows  worldly discipline enforced through ‘the cane’.</p><p>Let the Sahaja Yogi get the discipline from within, let him be  awakened from within. Look at its discipline with which you are moving.  You are moving your limbs with its discipline, with its waves. Who has  enforced discipline on the ocean’s waves? Sitting here you can tell the  time of high tide and low tide in London. Who has enforced its  discipline? You are trying to enforce someone else’s!? Learn to get into its discipline. Learn to grow with its signals and its mechanism. Its  machine is working. Don’t make any of your own. Just say, ‘let us get  into Sahaja Yoga, Let us go, let us invest time in Sahaja Yoga’. If you  wear a watch, it is for Sahaja Yoga. If you put an alarm, it should be  for Sahaja Yoga. …..Marathi words….See this, this age and this is Sahaja Yoga. ..Marathi…silence….</p><p>Not even a leaf in this world can move without its discipline. Become one with it; get into its harmony – Get fully harmonised with it; when  it rises you rise when it falls you fall. If we make something of our  own, we will not be in touch with it. You mold yourself with that. It  can happen only with Sahaja Yoga. It can not happen with anything else,  it can’t happen with any earthly thing of the world. There is only one  way, I have told you thousands of times, I am telling you again and  again; your fortress is ‘Nirvicharita (thoughtlessness). Find out in  Nirvicharita. You will know everything. Whatever you have to do, go into Nirvicharita. Do all worldly things in Nirvicharita, you will see that  it becomes dynamic. Who has seen the blooming of flowers, who has seen  fruits growing, who has seen the execution of all the worldly work? It  is happening; you are moving in the same dynamism, in the same living  thing. It is coming from Nirvicharita, is n’t it?. You sit in that  place, from where the whole world blooms. Make a habit of Nirvicharita,  try to be always in thoughtlessness. All the work of this world happens  through that and yours also will happen. All useless things will happen, but you have to operate the inner system yourself.</p><p>There is no age problem; no one is old. You are just born, maybe two  or four years. You are all small babies. There is no issue of age. You  have to be in Nirvicharita. This is your place, this is your wealth,  this is your strength, this is your power, this is your form, this is  your beauty, this is your life, Nirvichar. As soon as you become  thoughtless, the machine outside starts to fully spin in your hands. Be  in thoughtlessness. There, there is no time, no direction, nor anyone  can touch you. You will get to see the life process, how life blooms.  You will see its beauty, its ability. Its opulence, its truth; gaze from the place where the stream of life flows. But becoming ill-advised,  becoming a fool, how will it show to you?! Or heart becoming empty,  loveless, selfish, self-centered, thinking about oneself, thinking big  of oneself, how can it show you the path- being ugly, torturing. How  much beauty should be there in the movement and speed of Sahaja Yoga?  When you are doing it, there should be reverence. When you are raising  the Kundalini, there should be spirituality in your hands; you are  worshipping someone’s Kundalini, someone’s mother. How much respect you  should have? How much thought you should give.</p><p>In everything, in your behaviour, in your language, in your speech,  in your laughter, in your caress, in your crying, in everything you do,  your heart should be seen, vastness should be seen, the sky should be  seen. A glimpse of the purity of water should be seen inside you. The  glow of the sun should be seen on your face, the coolness of the moon  should flow from you. Like the air, you should be outgoing. Your life is pulsating in the lives of all, realise this and don’t play with your  life. Be very reverent and devoted and accept it with humility, the new  life which is being poured into us by Paramatma. Accept its love and  compassion. Just there is no need for taking a bath, no need for washing hands, nothing is required. Only the cleanliness of the heart is  required. Clean your heart. Pray, ‘God clean my heart’. Give up your  deceit and guile. Clean your heart. You are to get into the lotus of the heart. Clean your heart. Is my heart clean? Who are you cheating, who  are you telling lies to?</p><p>You are all one. It never happens that I am telling a particular  person. I am telling you all that you are all part of one body; even  that is My body, inside My body you are My projection. I am telling  Myself. Who other can I tell? Who is the other? If you get sick, I feel  the pain, as if I have become sick. And when you are happy, I feel I am  very happy. If you are not happy, I don’t feel happy about anything.  That is why I stay awake all day and night for your sake. The one who  gets, who has time, he should give time for this. Give full time for  this. Our ashram will be built, those of you who have money can donate.</p><p>You have to give because you spend so much, what did we gain by the  money you have spent so far? I don’t want your money, I don’t want to  spend your money. The ashram is being built for you, it is being built  for your brothers and sisters. They have to live there. They are getting children, they are realised; they have to go to school. There we need  someone to take care of these children. Give money for that. Without  money how can the building be brought up? Even if we get one Rupee from  your heart, It has a lot of significance. I am surprised. Such people  come here who hesitate to give one Rupee. There are no poor people here  if it were so it is ok. Even for giving one Rupee if they are miserly,  how can they be in Sahaja Yoga. When I hear this, I am surprised. They  bother you even for giving one Rupee or five Rupees. When you have  money, you donate, you have to give in thousands, in tens of thousands.  Who has given you the money? I do n’t want it. What need do I have?  Please give it to yourself. Give for your well being. You will live in  those ashrams with your kith and kin, I know. You do not have to live on freebies, live like a king. I don’t eat for free, you should also not  eat for free. Whatever you can contribute, contribute. If you have time, spare your time, if you can put in some hard work, do it. If you can  awaken Kundalini, do it if you can give realisation, give it If you can  remove bhoots, remove bhoots.</p><p>Contribute to Sahaja Yoga. If you don’t do it, your ego is not going  to die, your superego is not going to run away. Till you do something  for Sahaja Yoga, it will again bother you. ‘ Mother my head is caught  up, Mother my daughter ran away, Mataji, this happened to my father’. It will happen. I don’t do anything. Ganas also don’t do anything. The  bhoots will catch your weakness. They don’t trouble Me. Do you know why  they don’t catch Me? ‘What has Mataji given me, Mataji has so much to  him’. He had to get so much. He got it. What you got also is not less.  You don’t value what you got. You should be satisfied within. Catch hold of satisfaction from inside. Establish yourself on that satisfaction.  How should I tell you this, there is a computer for this, it has points. If you press one finger, your satisfaction will be awakened, if you  press one finger your innocence will be awakened, if you press one  finger truth will be awakened. This is all inside you, by pressing the  fingers like this, the entire program can be set. Shri Mataji keeps  doing this. In the first place, there should be innocence there. There  should be some satisfaction there, otherwise, you press the finger, what will come out from there-vacuum?!</p><p>There is nothing inside. One who has added satisfaction, he will  reach satisfaction. We are sitting in satisfaction at this time. We have reached righteousness. We are sitting in righteousness at this time.  All have accumulated wealth after burning the body for years and now it  is present before you. Like this, you have to keep adding everything,  add satisfaction, a lot of it. Come into innocence, come into  righteousness. Come into the truth, come into the beauty, Come into  love, you have a button for everything. How will it happen, how to do  it? Sahaja Yoga does n’t have to do it. It all happens. There is no such word like ‘How?’ in Sahaja Yoga.</p><p>You can earn whatever you want to be inside you. If you want  satisfaction, you can earn satisfaction. You can earn everything and  keep inside. Press a button and you will keep getting what you want. A  machine will manifest inside you. I don’t know how you will earn  these-You add your earning!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;-01-25 Talk To Sahaja Yogis: Must Listen Every Day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sahaja has been crea</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>灵性之路——从佛陀到三皈依</title>
    <link href="http://mataji.cn/2022/12/09/%E5%85%B6%E4%BB%96/%E4%BB%8E%E4%BD%9B%E9%99%80%E5%88%B0%E4%B8%89%E7%9A%88%E4%BE%9D/"/>
    <id>http://mataji.cn/2022/12/09/%E5%85%B6%E4%BB%96/%E4%BB%8E%E4%BD%9B%E9%99%80%E5%88%B0%E4%B8%89%E7%9A%88%E4%BE%9D/</id>
    <published>2022-12-09T07:05:27.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-08-30T15:38:47.632Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>灵性之路——从佛陀到三皈依：皈依佛，皈依法，皈依僧</p><p>有一次，偶然机会去了一次成都文殊院，看到里面的书，对佛陀三皈依的解释完全是错误的。因为没有觉者，就无法理解真理，这是超越思维的。所有非觉者写的书都是盲目的，盲人无法给盲人带路。</p><p>在我们的灵性升进中，我们常常也会迷失方向。而佛陀三皈依阐述了整个灵性的三大历程，从起点到终点，对于我们每个人的灵性有重大指导意义。</p><p>在此之前，我们先简单介绍一个佛陀。8000年前，即罗摩降世的年代，女神sita创造了两个特殊的人类。他们是宇宙持守者罗摩的儿子。其中一个后来降世为佛陀。</p><p>本质上来说，佛陀起初只是人类，后来成长为降世神祇的层次，掌管宇宙大我的自我部分。作为王子，他拥有漂亮的妻子和孩子，但最终他放弃了一切。他是门徒原理的代表，他追寻神的过程，正如我们在求道中所经历的一切。一开始，佛陀也是向外寻求的，遍访学者，读很多书。最终他失败了，完全放弃了，然后在菩提树下休息，这时太初之母给他自觉，之后佛陀开始传道。</p><p>佛陀最重要的工作是要去除人类的自我，教导人们无欲，去除所有不纯洁的欲望，使注意力走向内在，追寻内在灵的觉醒。佛陀并不是无神论，在当时那个年代，人们总是谈论神，把一切责任都归咎于神。所以佛陀改变了策略，就是不谈轮神，只是谈论自觉。因为没有自觉是不可能认识神的。</p><h3 id="皈依佛"><a href="#皈依佛" class="headerlink" title="皈依佛"></a><strong>皈依佛</strong></h3><p>有人说：“人人都可以成佛”。理论上是这样，因为每个人都拥有灵量和灵，但实际上只有少数人会得到自觉。佛从梵语翻译过来就是觉者的意思，意味着与上天的力量合一。</p><p>所以第一步，皈依佛，向真我顺服。起点已经非常高了。在佛教历史中，没有几个人真正获得自觉。各类宗教存在的目的都是教导正法，好为今天的自觉做准备工作，但宗教徒却大多走在错误的道路上。</p><p>如今，我们很多人已经获得自觉，但他们的注意力依然还在外在，而不是在内在的灵。他们常常忘记自己是觉醒的灵，保留了过去粗糙的习惯，甚至和普通人没有多大区别。比如，一些人已经获得自觉，却还在追寻那些虚假的导师或知识，或从世俗中学习一些粗糙的东西，用世俗的方式看待一切。这就是很多人虽然获得自觉，却无法快速进步的原因之一。你是觉者，我们要时刻去依靠神的力量，而不是他人的力量。比如，有的人担心地震或战争，有什么好担心的?你已经处于神的国度，上天的力量会保护你。他们没有意识到自己的力量。有的人保留了说脏话，或物质主意的习惯，这表示他们没有向真我的觉醒顺服。若一只狗变成了人类，它就不能保持狗的生活习惯。</p><p>所以你先要在自己身上实践，把注意力放在自己身上也是让你避免把注意力放在其他事物的方法。在实相中看，若你不妥当，怎能改善全世界。当你的注意力放在其他事物上，你必定知道自己有某些不妥，首先必须要纠正。</p><h3 id="皈依法"><a href="#皈依法" class="headerlink" title="皈依法"></a><strong>皈依法</strong></h3><p>不是外在的宗教，而是内在的法。这个法就是正法，我们知道摩西十诫，就是代表人类幻海的十个原子价。正法是灵性升进的基础。这个法指上天的律法，而不是人类的律法。比如，人类律法允许喝酒和吸烟，但这绝对是反神的。</p><p>这个法我们可以说是美德。比如，我们教导别人要爱他人。就像宗教都讲，要有爱，但实际上他们并没有爱。这不是外在的，而是内在的品质。比如，一个慷慨的人什么也不需要做，他就是慷慨本身，这种特质是内在的。而一个吝啬的人修行，就要很费力的去实践慷慨。我们的教育也是如此，很多道德教育都是制约，不是真正内在的美德。这种正法可以透过唤醒我们的幻海而唤醒。</p><p>每当我们犯错，违背正法的时候，我们的灵性就会下跌，轮穴会阻塞。即使我们得到自觉后，犯错也会被上天的力量惩罚，甚至比普通人更严重，因为普通人是无知的，而你不是。所以，我们要很小心尽量不要去犯错。即使犯了错，也要祈求神的宽恕。因为人类会犯错，然后我们会成长。神会宽恕我们。但我们不应感到内疚，或者找借口逃避自己的错误。没有人可以和神玩把戏，祂是全知的。祂会容忍你到一定程度，若依然不改正。祂就会暴露你，或者狠狠的惩罚你。最糟糕的，就是把你抛出神的国度，跳出进化。</p><p>当我们觉醒，自动会知道什么是上天的正法。因为生命能量会告诉你，随着冥想和内省，也会自动成长为有正法的人，然后你不会喜欢任何非正法的行为。</p><p>最大的问题依然是自我。人们总意味自己做了伟大的事情，自己可以解决问题，管理自己，这是没有成熟的标志。要做母亲的孩子，把一切问题交托给神，然后祂就会接管。</p><h3 id="皈依僧"><a href="#皈依僧" class="headerlink" title="皈依僧"></a><strong>皈依僧</strong></h3><p>僧就是集体。佛陀那时，人们放弃了家庭，过着集体的生活。虽然，现代我们不需要放弃家庭，但我们需要明白，谁才是我们的亲人。不是你的父母，妻子或儿女，而是觉者。他们都是宇宙大我的一部人。但那些世俗的关系，他们与神没有任何连接，还不属于集体的一部分。但并不意味着我们不去照顾他们，不爱他们。</p><p>所以真正的集体，属于神的集体。属神的人要常常在一起。这是灵性成就的最高方式或者是最终方式。因为滴水要融入大海，否则我们都是自我中心的人。看看我们的身体，各个器官都是完全一体的，它们没有自我。</p><p>过集体生活，能很大程度上克服我们的自我。要与集体在一起，至少每月一次，旅行的方式也是可以的。不来到集体，不成为集体的一部分，你永远不能知道集体的价值。集体是很伟大的，能给你许多力量、满足感和喜乐。在霎哈嘉瑜伽，首先要将注意力放在集体之上。就算开始时有所欠缺，也不要紧。你要来到集体，但不要批评别人。要反身自问，为甚么人人都能享受集体，我却坐在一旁批评，我有什么问题？如果你能将注意力。放在自己有甚么缺点之上，而不是找寻别人的错处，这样你便更能享受集体。自我就我下降。</p><p>神的注意力在集体上。一朵花要是短暂离开树木是可以存活的，但长久就会枯萎。我们必须从树的主体吸收营养，否则就会凋零，最终被淘汰。</p><p>而且我们都是整体的一部分，没有人可以单独上升。当我们集体冥想时，可以很好的集体洁净。我的导师举个例子：当只有一滴水的时候，你无法洁净自己。当去到很多水的地方，才可以洁净自己。另一个例子是：很多鸟被网住，一只鸟是无法挣脱的，当所有鸟一起努力，才可以挣脱束缚。</p><p>当我们真正达到修行的目标，即无疑惑觉醒，那就是集体的。这是终点，灵性的很多事情都需要集体成就，而不是个人。集体也像一面镜子，可以照出我们所有的问题，也可以透过集体的力量洁净我们。</p><p>这就是佛陀三皈依的真正含义，包含我们灵性的从始至终，若我们能很好的实践这三个原理，就很容易达到神的国度。</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;灵性之路——从佛陀到三皈依：皈依佛，皈依法，皈依僧&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有一次，偶然机会去了一次成都文殊院，看到里面的书，对佛陀三皈依的解释完全是错误的。因为没有觉者，就无法理解真理，这是超越思维的。所有非觉者写的书都是盲目的，盲人无法给盲人带路。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在我们的灵性升进</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="个人原创" scheme="http://mataji.cn/categories/%E4%B8%AA%E4%BA%BA%E5%8E%9F%E5%88%9B/"/>
    
    
    <category term="佛陀" scheme="http://mataji.cn/tags/%E4%BD%9B%E9%99%80/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>因果和业力</title>
    <link href="http://mataji.cn/2022/11/16/%E5%85%B6%E4%BB%96/%E5%9B%A0%E6%9E%9C%E5%92%8C%E4%B8%9A%E5%8A%9B/"/>
    <id>http://mataji.cn/2022/11/16/%E5%85%B6%E4%BB%96/%E5%9B%A0%E6%9E%9C%E5%92%8C%E4%B8%9A%E5%8A%9B/</id>
    <published>2022-11-16T08:58:15.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-09-10T13:48:17.435Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>看到很多人在谈论业力，但却不知道业力到底是什么？业力又如何影响我们。</p><p>我们可以将这一原理成为因果律。俗话说:好有好报，恶有恶报，不是不报，时候未到。也许很多人不相信，但它的确存在。</p><p>业力我们可以说是所有行为产生的结果。佛教谈论因果特别多。俗话说:菩萨畏因，众生畏果。说明一切苦难和好运都是因导致的。若无法超越因，就无法超越业力。</p><p>因果律从何而来，这是神用来平衡人的行为，籍此来纠正人类，回归平衡。例如，去深水游泳，结果就是可能被淹死。这就是因果，所以人会学习回归平衡。女神的力量是抛物线运动，很多国家会把马蹄形或马蹄作为吉祥物，辟邪。因为那是抛物线，散发生命能量。若我们去爱一个人，爱的能量会返回来。若是去恨一个人，那个恨的能量也会回来。</p><p>大家一定听说过，有一些巫术可以诅咒他人，但那个施展诅咒的人也会付出代价。甚至我们诅咒他人，也会受苦，尽管几乎不起作用，因为那个人没有连接到整体，否则诅咒就会生效。</p><p>业力之所以产生是因为自我。当我们做了好事或坏事，都会产生好和坏的果报。很多佛教徒都在做好的业报，但依然在业力之中，好的果报的确可以让人更接近神，更有机会获得自觉。但实际上，我们是不需要自我的，好的业也要超越。</p><p>自我首先产生的原因是反神。当亚当和夏娃吃了禁果之后，神的震怒发动了大洪水。在基督教中，把自我称为原罪。人类开始发展自我意识，动物和植物都没有自我意识。以至于到今天，人们甚至不认为神存在，祂是造物主。这是自我产生的第一个原因。我们有了虚幻的认同，我是张三，李四等，我是中国人，我是教师等各种虚幻的认同，然后又开始认为我们盖了房子，养育了他人等等虚幻。</p><p>有一个笑话，有一个人骑着驴子，然后肩上扛着袋子。他认为他是做事者，却不知道驴才是做事者。同样的例子，一个农民以为自己种农产品养育他人，却不知道实际是大地母亲养育万物。我们把一切风调雨顺都视作理所当然。就像冠状病毒来了，大家都说只能靠免疫系统。免疫系统是什么？那是女神的保护力量。</p><p>所以，神是真正的做事者，当一个人开始认为自己做了什么了不起的事，自我就产生了，一个人变得愚蠢。圣人无为而治，不居功！大地母亲养育万物却从不炫耀，她同样可以思考和组织，地震就是大地母亲的杰作，用来惩罚没有贞洁或黑巫术的人等。</p><p>当我们去做好事，会积累好的业，做坏事也会积累坏的业。即使因为无知，错误依然是错误。比如媒婆，针灸治病，误导他人都会积累很坏的业力，不仅会受苦，获得自觉的机会也会减少。</p><p><strong>那么如何克服和去除自我？</strong></p><p>佛陀谈论因果和自我最多，因为祂在宇宙大我掌管自我。尽管佛陀获得自觉，但祂不明白灵量，也不明白重生。</p><p>直到耶稣的降世，人们无法克服业力。耶稣带给人重生的意识，祂以复活告诉世人，身体是虚幻的，灵才是我们的本质。祂注定要被钉死十字架，若没有这戏剧，人类的额轮无法打开。祂因人类的罪而死，然后人类才有了超越因果的可能。</p><p>耶稣掌管我们的额轮，只有唤醒内在的耶稣，祂才会真正起作用，会吸收我们的自我和超我，只有自我被吸收，业力才会消失。要唤醒耶稣，就必须唤醒我们内在的灵量，我发的视频已经有唤醒灵量的方法。</p><p>恒河水也可以消除一些业力。我知道很多人嘲笑印度人使用恒河的方式。很多东西超出人的理解，恒河是从天上引下来的，所以被称为圣河，可以净化心灵。在中国，有很多人去冈仁波齐朝圣，因为那是天父湿婆神呆过的地方，普通人是无法理解背后原理的。</p><p>我们根据业力出生在不同的地区和家庭，生辰八字，占星术对普通人都起作用。当年，我读高中时就喜欢看算命，当时就想:若一切都被注定，那我岂不是活在笼子里，直到找到真理，我开始超越了因果。</p><p>所以想要克服业力的朋友，需要唤醒灵量，获得自觉。不想克服自我的，我想告诉大家，不要做错事，现在上天的毁灭力量相当活跃。</p><p>暂时就分享这么多，下次分享什么是自觉（觉醒）或开悟，已经觉醒后的能力。</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;看到很多人在谈论业力，但却不知道业力到底是什么？业力又如何影响我们。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们可以将这一原理成为因果律。俗话说:好有好报，恶有恶报，不是不报，时候未到。也许很多人不相信，但它的确存在。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;业力我们可以说是所有行为产生的结果。佛教谈论因果特别多。俗话说:</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="个人原创" scheme="http://mataji.cn/categories/%E4%B8%AA%E4%BA%BA%E5%8E%9F%E5%88%9B/"/>
    
    
    <category term="业力" scheme="http://mataji.cn/tags/%E4%B8%9A%E5%8A%9B/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>灵性升进的基础-精微能量系统图说明</title>
    <link href="http://mataji.cn/2022/04/15/%E8%87%AA%E8%A7%89%E5%92%8C%E5%86%A5%E6%83%B3/%E7%81%B5%E6%80%A7%E5%8D%87%E8%BF%9B%E7%9A%84%E5%9F%BA%E7%A1%80-%E7%B2%BE%E5%BE%AE%E8%83%BD%E9%87%8F%E7%B3%BB%E7%BB%9F%E5%9B%BE%E8%AF%B4%E6%98%8E/"/>
    <id>http://mataji.cn/2022/04/15/%E8%87%AA%E8%A7%89%E5%92%8C%E5%86%A5%E6%83%B3/%E7%81%B5%E6%80%A7%E5%8D%87%E8%BF%9B%E7%9A%84%E5%9F%BA%E7%A1%80-%E7%B2%BE%E5%BE%AE%E8%83%BD%E9%87%8F%E7%B3%BB%E7%BB%9F%E5%9B%BE%E8%AF%B4%E6%98%8E/</id>
    <published>2022-04-15T09:09:32.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-04-15T09:19:27.362Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>今天我们来介绍人体精微能量系统图。目前人类所了解的都是人体医学图，只能治疗身体，无法治疗不治之症，因为他们不明白病因，几乎所有的不治之症都是身心病。若我们了解精微能量系统图，能够去运作这个系统，几乎可以治愈所有疾病。未来专门写一篇文章来介绍医学与精微能量系统图的关系。</p><p>但今天我们谈论的不是医学，而是精微能量系统如何影响我们，又如何透过精微能量系统改善我们的身体，精神等所有不平衡，如何启发特质，获得喜乐和平安，以及实现灵性的升进。</p><p>这张图我们称之为三脉七轮图。神首先创造了宇宙大我，再根据宇宙大我创造了人类，甚至我们的大地母亲有着同样的精微能量系统，比如美国代表喉轮，而英国代表左心轮。首先我们介绍三条经脉，代表神的三种力量，也就是老子所说的三，三生万物，神透过这三种力量创造了万物。这些知识自远古时代就存在，只不过那时修行的人很少，都是导师考验门徒后秘密传授。</p><p><img src="https://p6.toutiaoimg.com/origin/pgc-image/5d99a6d744ec401ca24ce85fb60aa75a?from=pc" alt="灵性升进的基础——精微能量系统图说明"></p><h3 id="左脉—愿望的力量"><a href="#左脉—愿望的力量" class="headerlink" title="左脉—愿望的力量"></a><strong>左脉—愿望的力量</strong></h3><p>我们将图上左侧蓝色的经脉称为左脉，医学上对应左交感神经。有点类似于中国文化的阴，图上有个月亮，也可以叫月亮脉。阴阳平衡指的就是要平衡左脉和右脉，而保持在中脉。</p><p>左脉代表愿望的力量，掌管我们的愿望，情绪情感及过去，在进化过程中所有淘汰的事物都在左脉之中。偏向左脉的人容易出心理问题，性格内向，缺乏自信心，优柔寡断，情绪敏感等等。心理学研究的是左脉，而医学则研究的是右脉。所以，所有任何左脉的问题，通过洁净左脉就能恢复平衡的人格，治疗一切心理和情绪的问题。</p><h3 id="右脉—行动的力量"><a href="#右脉—行动的力量" class="headerlink" title="右脉—行动的力量"></a><strong>右脉—行动的力量</strong></h3><p>右脉也可以称为太阳脉，图上为黄色经脉，医学对应右交感神经，代表行动的力量。掌管我们的行动，思考，计划未来，也代表身体。处于右边的人一般比较强势，自我取向，未来取向，行动力强，容易暴躁发脾气。</p><h3 id="中脉—进化的力量"><a href="#中脉—进化的力量" class="headerlink" title="中脉—进化的力量"></a><strong>中脉—进化的力量</strong></h3><p>中脉代表进化的力量，我们一切进化的结果都储存在中脉。医学上对应副交感神经。中脉给予我们平衡。一般来说我们只能使用左脉或右脉的力量，比如我们做运动会令心跳加速，但中脉使心跳恢复正常的力量。中脉也代表当下，只有处于无思虑才能保持在中脉。当中脉被打开，就会给予我们消耗过度的左右两脉能量，令一个人回归平衡。我们的灵性也只能透过中脉完成进化，它是灵量的通道。</p><p><img src="https://p6.toutiaoimg.com/origin/pgc-image/2a7256dd0f704936989dcd05612c3446.png?from=pc" alt="灵性升进的基础——精微能量系统图说明"></p><p>此图为大地母亲的创造，三圈半代表了灵量</p><h3 id="灵量—我们内在的母亲"><a href="#灵量—我们内在的母亲" class="headerlink" title="灵量—我们内在的母亲"></a><strong>灵量—我们内在的母亲</strong></h3><p>灵量在我们骶骨三角骨，属于我们每个人的母亲，她是愿望的力量，神的剩余力量，一直等待被唤醒。当她被唤醒穿越上面6个轮穴，我们可以说一个人获得了灵性的觉醒。灵量会清洁我们的轮穴并启发轮穴的特质。灵量是人类突破觉醒的起点，如同种子的胚芽，只有启动胚芽才能开花结果。因此，只有唤醒灵量才能获得觉醒，没有其他途经。</p><h3 id="根轮—纯真和智慧的来源"><a href="#根轮—纯真和智慧的来源" class="headerlink" title="根轮—纯真和智慧的来源"></a><strong>根轮—纯真和智慧的来源</strong></h3><p>根轮特性是纯真，向小孩子一样天真无邪。根轮掌管我们的排泄功能，当灵量升起，便停止照顾骨盆神经丛的排泄功能，而是支撑灵量的工作。所以，根轮是灵性的根基，如同大树的根，若根轮不妥当，升进如同空中楼阁。</p><p>纯真是不可被毁灭的，只会被过度的性行为造成的乌云覆盖。透过洁净根轮，艾滋病也可以治愈。</p><p>同时根轮也是智慧的来源，没有纯真的人会做出各种荒唐的事。</p><h3 id="腹轮—创造力和美感"><a href="#腹轮—创造力和美感" class="headerlink" title="腹轮—创造力和美感"></a><strong>腹轮—创造力和美感</strong></h3><p>医学表现为主动脉神经丛。这个中心供应我们思考，计划未来所需要的能量。它能把脂肪细胞转化为脑细胞，供应大脑的需要。运动也会消耗这轮穴的能量。</p><p>此轮穴也被称为真知轮，代表上天的纯洁知识。若是被亡灵附体或跟随假导师会有左边问题，过度活跃的思维和身体会有右边的问题，尤其是肝脏。同时腹轮也带给我们美感和创造力。一般做艺术的对这个轮穴消耗比较大。</p><h3 id="脐轮—慷慨，平安与满足感"><a href="#脐轮—慷慨，平安与满足感" class="headerlink" title="脐轮—慷慨，平安与满足感"></a><strong>脐轮—慷慨，平安与满足感</strong></h3><p>医学上代表太阳神经丛，此中心供应使我们生命持续的力量。代表正法和进化，特质是慷慨和满足感。左脐轮代表家庭，家户女神，妻子照顾家庭和孩子表现的就是左脐轮特质，若一个人家庭出了问题，左脐轮就有问题。右边代表至高天后，如国母，代表公共利益，政治统治。也是财富的象征，右脐轮很好的人会赚到很多钱。</p><h3 id="幻海—导师的力量"><a href="#幻海—导师的力量" class="headerlink" title="幻海—导师的力量"></a><strong>幻海—导师的力量</strong></h3><p>又称迷幻的海洋，中间像梯子一样断开了中脉，这是人类生活在虚幻中的原因。绿色的圈，代表导师原理，原始宗师十次降世地球教导人类正法，并以十个原子价保持我们的正法，祂们都住在我们的幻海。当幻海被唤醒，我们就可以穿越迷幻的海洋到达实相。跟随假导师，违背上天的正法，负面的，不道德的人会有此轮穴的问题，同时会处在神的毁灭力量当中。若幻海被纠正，一个人自动变得有正法和道德。女神的力量保护我们的生存和健康，但导师给予我们知识，让我们真正得到成长。</p><h3 id="心轮—安全感的本质-灵的本质：真理-意识-喜乐"><a href="#心轮—安全感的本质-灵的本质：真理-意识-喜乐" class="headerlink" title="心轮—安全感的本质 灵的本质：真理-意识-喜乐"></a><strong>心轮—安全感的本质 灵的本质：真理-意识-喜乐</strong></h3><p>位于脊柱胸骨之后。十二岁之前，此中心产生抗体，保护我们免受负能量攻击。心轮中部特质，安全感，自信心和勇气。心轮左边是灵体，人的本质所在，喜乐，爱心和平安的来源，也代表母亲。右心轮则代表父亲，丈夫，责任感。</p><h3 id="喉轮—沟通与静观"><a href="#喉轮—沟通与静观" class="headerlink" title="喉轮—沟通与静观"></a><strong>喉轮—沟通与静观</strong></h3><p>掌管耳、喉、头、舌、牙等部位。此中心负责与别人的沟通能力。医学表现为头部神经丛。左喉轮代表自尊，男女分际，右边是甜美的行为和语言，中间是沟通，静观能力。自卑感，罪疚感来自左喉轮，意味着我们在犯错，可以称为罪的工价。</p><h3 id="额轮—宽恕的海洋"><a href="#额轮—宽恕的海洋" class="headerlink" title="额轮—宽恕的海洋"></a><strong>额轮—宽恕的海洋</strong></h3><p>也称为宽恕轮，在视神经丛的位置。照顾脑下垂体和松果腺，分别表现为自我和超我。耶稣掌管额轮中部，佛陀掌管右额轮的自我。当额轮被唤醒，耶稣就宽恕了我们过往所犯的罪。</p><p>额轮是一个非常大的课题，因为自我和超我封闭了头顶，令我们失去与神的连接。而我们目前对真理认知都来自于这两个气球，要认识实相，就必须超越思维的影响，这也是通过冥想进入无思虑的重要性。这两个气球令人变得愚蠢而又傲慢。自我和超我是思维的产物，所以那些思维越多，阅读越多的人自我和超我更大，而真理却在无思虑中。所以老子说：为学日益，为道日损。</p><p><img src="https://p6.toutiaoimg.com/origin/pgc-image/bb9867f282a64570b8ee388cf6f16cae?from=pc" alt="灵性升进的基础——精微能量系统图说明"></p><h3 id="顶轮—整合-千莲盛开"><a href="#顶轮—整合-千莲盛开" class="headerlink" title="顶轮—整合 千莲盛开"></a><strong>顶轮—整合 千莲盛开</strong></h3><p>有一千条神经从，就像盛开的莲花，代表整合。头部拥有其他所有轮穴的宝座。当1000条神经丛都被启发，一个人就获得了完全的觉醒，可以直接跳出轮回到达天国。</p><p>当我们启动了这个能量系统，就可以去验证所有的知识。获得觉醒的方法这里就不写了，可留言，无偿提供给需要的人。</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;今天我们来介绍人体精微能量系统图。目前人类所了解的都是人体医学图，只能治疗身体，无法治疗不治之症，因为他们不明白病因，几乎所有的不治之症都是身心病。若我们了解精微能量系统图，能够去运作这个系统，几乎可以治愈所有疾病。未来专门写一篇文章来介绍医学与精微能量系统图的关系。&lt;/p</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="自觉和冥想" scheme="http://mataji.cn/categories/%E8%87%AA%E8%A7%89%E5%92%8C%E5%86%A5%E6%83%B3/"/>
    
    
    <category term="自觉" scheme="http://mataji.cn/tags/%E8%87%AA%E8%A7%89/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>10分钟获得自觉的方法</title>
    <link href="http://mataji.cn/2022/04/15/%E8%87%AA%E8%A7%89%E5%92%8C%E5%86%A5%E6%83%B3/10%E5%88%86%E9%92%9F%E8%8E%B7%E5%BE%97%E8%87%AA%E8%A7%89%E7%9A%84%E6%96%B9%E6%B3%95/"/>
    <id>http://mataji.cn/2022/04/15/%E8%87%AA%E8%A7%89%E5%92%8C%E5%86%A5%E6%83%B3/10%E5%88%86%E9%92%9F%E8%8E%B7%E5%BE%97%E8%87%AA%E8%A7%89%E7%9A%84%E6%96%B9%E6%B3%95/</id>
    <published>2022-04-15T09:03:32.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-04-15T09:17:37.988Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>关于什么是开悟或自觉，我已经在之前文章作了详细介绍。今天我们主要分享实际操作篇，真正去体验真理，获得自觉，而不是空洞的谈论理论。</p><p>如果在古代，你向人们说可以登上月球，没有人会相信，因为受限于当时的科技。在灵性领域，同样如此，10分钟获得自觉可能吗？在以前，即使你行各种苦行，无论你如何努力，都无法获得自觉。即使降世神祇也无法给予自觉，因为时机没有成熟。</p><p>但事情在1970年5月5日发生了转变，由于神的恩赐，人类的集体的顶轮被打开，这使人们大规模获得自觉成为可能。这是灵性史上最伟大的事情，过往有很多降世神祇做了无数工作才到达这个段。如同我们的科技建立在巨人的肩膀上。</p><img src="https://p6.toutiaoimg.com/origin/pgc-image/9e68871d7eb143d89679055b18b51900?from=pc" alt="10分钟获得自觉的方法（实践篇）" style="zoom:50%;" /><p>多说无益，我们还是直接进入实践篇。只有获得自觉，我们才能谈论更多深入的知识。下面的篇幅我会详细介绍实践方法和原理。关于获得自觉的基础，精微能量系统图请看之前文章。这里只介绍原理。自觉意味着个体与上天力量的连结。</p><p><strong>如何达到？所有的机制早就内置在我们的身体系统，与思维毫无关系。只需要唤醒我们图中三角骨里的灵量，当灵量上升，穿越中间的通道，刺穿顶轮，一个人开始连接到上天的力量，即宇宙大我，这就是自觉。</strong></p><p>灵量是我们内在愿望的力量，太初母性力量，她是我们每一个人的母亲，记录我们历世的一切。她一直等待被唤醒，给予我们自觉。她一直在沉睡，如同种子的胚芽，一旦胚芽被唤醒，种子才会开花结果，这就是重生。若一个人没有自觉，我们内在所有力量都无法表达。</p><p>所以，我们必须拥有纯洁的愿望去获取，否则她不会起作用。当我们去做事，首先产生的是欲望，然后才做出行动，对吧？</p><p>在准备唤醒灵量，我们需要做一些准备。首先找一个比较安静，不受干扰的地方。然后脱掉鞋子和袜子，坐在地上。因为我们的鞋子和袜子都是人工化的物品，会隔绝与大地母亲能量流通，大地母亲可以帮助我们吸走不好的能量，帮助我们获得自觉。</p><p>然后我们有一些手部动作，都发生在左侧，因为左脉是我们愿望的力量，而右脉属于行动的力量，我们用右手去做出行动。然后透过一些确认语句或口诀，去打开我们的轮穴，这样灵量才有通道上升。在整个过程中，不要思考，用心去做，因为思维会阻碍额轮。建议可以使用霎哈嘉瑜伽创始人玛塔吉的照片，因为幻海的悬梯需要通过真导师的力量填充，后面附图。同时可以点上一根蜡烛，火元素对左脉很有帮助，而光元素则对额轮有帮助，同时可以燃烧一些负面能量。</p><p>最后，我必须强调一点，不要认为自己做了什么，神才是做事者。比如：当你吃了食物，不是你在消化食物，而是你的胃。在整个过程中，最好保持无思虑，用心去做。若没有获得自觉，可以试图多做几次，因为有的人轮穴被破坏的很严重。</p><p><img src="https://p6.toutiaoimg.com/origin/pgc-image/e6e04509ca3c48d59ec5d25d59d958d9?from=pc" alt="10分钟获得自觉的方法（实践篇）"></p><p>第一步中，左心轮是我们的灵体所在。第二步中，左上腹是导师原理的能量中心，我们可以问这几个问题。整个过程，我们把注意力放在内在，闭上眼睛。</p><p><img src="https://p6.toutiaoimg.com/origin/pgc-image/c977f405e21c432abcb7fa6ba78ff63f?from=pc" alt="10分钟获得自觉的方法（实践篇）"></p><p>第三步，右手放在左下腹，这是上天纯洁知识的能量中心，6次确认语句，因为这个轮穴有6块花瓣。第四部是导师的能量中心，原始宗师主要以10个形相降世，建立我们的幻海。在中国，老子和孔子都是原始宗师的化身。</p><p><img src="https://p6.toutiaoimg.com/origin/pgc-image/19d3e3b635b9455794313ee93964a152?from=pc" alt="10分钟获得自觉的方法（实践篇）"></p><p>心轮有12块花瓣，所以用心去说12次，为了唤醒我们内在的灵，灵是我们的本质所在，神的反应。</p><p><img src="https://p6.toutiaoimg.com/origin/pgc-image/71dcaab802c2416db60460b1d4778c2b?from=pc" alt="10分钟获得自觉的方法（实践篇）"></p><p>第六步，我们用右手按住左喉轮，用心说16次，我没有罪疚感。因为罪疚感会导致这个轮穴罪恶，只是用心去说，会起作用，打开这轮穴通道。</p><p><img src="https://p6.toutiaoimg.com/origin/pgc-image/7f44022427da496baf91516ef7957e20?from=pc" alt="10分钟获得自觉的方法（实践篇）"></p><p>第八步，右手放在我们后额轮，我们枕头的地方，头微微向上仰，这里，我们要寻求神的宽恕。</p><p>第九步，我们请求上天给予我们自觉。我们的右手按住头部脑囱的位置，同时顺时针用掌心旋转头皮，令头骨软化，同时使用确认语句作出请求。</p><p><img src="https://p6.toutiaoimg.com/origin/pgc-image/ee45ff2286c74517a8f754ecd42343ba?from=pc" alt="10分钟获得自觉的方法（实践篇）"></p><img src="https://p6.toutiaoimg.com/origin/pgc-image/ecf86b630c7c414fb58483c774672bb1?from=pc" alt="10分钟获得自觉的方法（实践篇）" style="zoom:50%;" /><p>​                                               霎哈嘉瑜伽创始人玛塔吉，给予成千上万人自觉</p><p>现在，我们可以将手放在头顶上方，离头更高的位置，去感应是否有热风和凉风从头顶渗透出来，然后注意力放在头顶静坐一会。看看手上是否有凉风和热风。热风代表阻塞，凉风代表轮穴较好，手指可能会有麻和胀，或微痛的感觉，那是轮穴阻塞的原因，每个手指都对应不同的轮穴。一旦感觉到新的知觉，恭喜你，获得了自觉。</p><p>获得自觉只是灵性的起始点，我们只是打开了顶轮，取得与上天力量的合一。我们先打开顶部，然后需要透过上天的力量来打地基。种子发芽了，还需要水和阳光才能开花结果，对吧！下方轮穴会有阻塞，需要通过适当的方法去洁净，更多的唤醒轮穴的神祇和特质，好使更多的灵量上升，灵量可以纠正我们所有轮穴的不平衡，表现在外在，我们的情绪，健康，精神和物质等一切都会改善。</p><p>自觉后我们需要恒常的练习入静，巩固自觉，否则顶轮可能再次关闭。自觉的好处，我们还是用一篇文章再详细介绍。毕竟，若没有极大的好处，我们为什么去追寻呢？之后我们再介绍如何冥想，如何平衡能量系统等。</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;关于什么是开悟或自觉，我已经在之前文章作了详细介绍。今天我们主要分享实际操作篇，真正去体验真理，获得自觉，而不是空洞的谈论理论。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;如果在古代，你向人们说可以登上月球，没有人会相信，因为受限于当时的科技。在灵性领域，同样如此，10分钟获得自觉可能吗？在以前，即使</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="自觉和冥想" scheme="http://mataji.cn/categories/%E8%87%AA%E8%A7%89%E5%92%8C%E5%86%A5%E6%83%B3/"/>
    
    
    <category term="自觉" scheme="http://mataji.cn/tags/%E8%87%AA%E8%A7%89/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
